<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Computational Pathology Group - highlights</title><link href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/feeds/highlights.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/</id><updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Camelyon16 published in JAMA</title><link href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/highlights/camelyon16-published-in-jama/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:diagnijmegen.github.io,2017-12-01:/website-pathology/highlights/camelyon16-published-in-jama/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Diagnostic Image Analysis Group organized Camelyon16, the first medical image analysis challenge with whole slide digital pathology images in 2016. The competition was a great success, and several of the submitted software solutions outperformed human pathologists in the detection of lymph node metastases. The results of Camelyon16 were published …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Diagnostic Image Analysis Group organized Camelyon16, the first medical image analysis challenge with whole slide digital pathology images in 2016. The competition was a great success, and several of the submitted software solutions outperformed human pathologists in the detection of lymph node metastases. The results of Camelyon16 were published in JAMA and covered by the national Dutch television show Nieuwsuur.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>NOS news article</title><link href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/highlights/nos-news-article/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:diagnijmegen.github.io,2017-03-04:/website-pathology/highlights/nos-news-article/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jeroen van der Laak has contributed to a &lt;a href="https://nos.nl/artikel/2161091-computer-kan-kanker-beter-herkennen-dan-patholoog.html"&gt; news article&lt;/a&gt; from NOS about the success of Google's deep learning-based algorithm for the automatic detection of breast cancer metastasis in sentinel lymphnodes. The algorithm was trained using data from the grand challenge CAMELYON16, organized by members of the CP group. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jeroen van der Laak has contributed to a &lt;a href="https://nos.nl/artikel/2161091-computer-kan-kanker-beter-herkennen-dan-patholoog.html"&gt; news article&lt;/a&gt; from NOS about the success of Google's deep learning-based algorithm for the automatic detection of breast cancer metastasis in sentinel lymphnodes. The algorithm was trained using data from the grand challenge CAMELYON16, organized by members of the CP group. The algorithm outperfoms pathologists as decribed in the resulting &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.02442"&gt; paper&lt;/a&gt;. More info can be found on the &lt;a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2017/03/assisting-pathologists-in-detecting.html"&gt;Google AI Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>