<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Computational Pathology Group - highlights</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/feeds/highlights.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/</id><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Nathan Kaufman timely topics lecture for Jeroen van der Laak at USCAP 2019</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/nathan-kaufman-lecture-van-der-laak-uscap19/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2019-03-22:/highlights/nathan-kaufman-lecture-van-der-laak-uscap19/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/jeroen-van-der-laak/"&gt;Jeroen van der Laak&lt;/a&gt; was honored as Nathan Kaufman timely topics lecturer at the &lt;a href="https://www.xcdsystem.com/uscap/program/2019/index.cfm?pgid=145"&gt;108th annual meeting&lt;/a&gt; of the United States and Canadian Academy of Pathology (&lt;a href="https://www.uscap.org/"&gt;USCAP&lt;/a&gt;). His keynote lecture titled 'The Rise of Artificial Intelligence: Impact on Advanced Diagnostics in Health Care' was held inside the impressive Potomac Ballroom …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/jeroen-van-der-laak/"&gt;Jeroen van der Laak&lt;/a&gt; was honored as Nathan Kaufman timely topics lecturer at the &lt;a href="https://www.xcdsystem.com/uscap/program/2019/index.cfm?pgid=145"&gt;108th annual meeting&lt;/a&gt; of the United States and Canadian Academy of Pathology (&lt;a href="https://www.uscap.org/"&gt;USCAP&lt;/a&gt;). His keynote lecture titled 'The Rise of Artificial Intelligence: Impact on Advanced Diagnostics in Health Care' was held inside the impressive Potomac Ballroom, in the Gaylord National Resort &amp;amp; Convention Center at the National Harber, Maryland. The lecture was witnessed by 3500 clinicians, researchers and other interested parties. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="USCAP" src="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/images/news/USCAP_2.jpeg"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The  Education  Committee of USCAP established  the  &lt;a href="https://www.uscap.org/public/documents/Kaufman_TimelyTopics_Info_VER7.pdf"&gt;Timely  Topics Lecture&lt;/a&gt; in  1982  at  the  suggestion  of  Dr.  Nathan  Kaufman.  It  was  initially  conceived  as  a  lecture  by  a  prominent  individual  in  the  field  of  pathology  to  address  a  “timely  topic”  but  has  evolved  into  a  sophisticated  presentation,  generally  by  a  clinician  or  researcher,  whose  integrated  relationship  with  pathology  moves  the  discipline  forward with contemporary ideas, innovative methods, and futuristic technology. This lecture is regarded as a great honor within the USCAP sphere.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>JBHI's special issue 'Computational Pathology' now accepting submissions</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/special-issue-jbhi/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2019-03-20:/highlights/special-issue-jbhi/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computational Pathology embodies the synergy of Digital Pathology, Medical Image Analysis, Computer Vision, and Machine Learning. The huge amount of information and data available in multi-gigapixel histopathology images makes digital pathology the perfect use case for advanced image analysis techniques. For this reason, deep learning and artificial intelligence have successfully …&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Computational Pathology embodies the synergy of Digital Pathology, Medical Image Analysis, Computer Vision, and Machine Learning. The huge amount of information and data available in multi-gigapixel histopathology images makes digital pathology the perfect use case for advanced image analysis techniques. For this reason, deep learning and artificial intelligence have successfully powered computational pathology research in recent years. Recent scientific events on computational pathology, such as the MICCAI 2018 workshop on Computational Pathology (COMPAY), the European Conference on Digital Pathology (ECDP), the Computational Pathology Symposium at the European Conference of Pathology (ECP), among others, have generated a substantial pool of original research work in this discipline.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of this special issue is to attract and highlight the latest developments in computational pathology, and feature papers proposing state-of-the-art solutions in the field of digital pathology using advanced image analysis and artificial intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Topics of interest include, but are not limited to:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Artificial intelligence and Deep Learning for Computational Pathology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stain normalization/standardization&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detection, classification and segmentation of tissue structures (cells, glands etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Detection and discovery of predictive and prognostic tissue biomarkers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Whole-slide image analysis&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Registration of whole-slide images&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Immunohistochemistry scoring&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multiplexed staining&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unlabeled multiplexing&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crowdsourcing for ground truth collection and machine learning applications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Applications of computational pathology in the clinic&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Guest Editors&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/francesco-ciompi/"&gt;Dr. Francesco Ciompi&lt;/a&gt;
(francesco.ciompi@radboudumc.nl)
Diagnostic Image Analysis Group, Dept. of Pathology, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.tue.nl/en/research/researchers/mitko-veta/"&gt;Dr. Mitko Veta&lt;/a&gt;
(m.veta@tue.nl)
Eindhoven University of Technology, Eindhoven, The Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/jeroen-van-der-laak/"&gt;Prof. Jeroen van der Laak&lt;/a&gt;
(jeroen.vanderlaak@radboudumc.nl)
Diagnostic Image Analysis Group, Dept. of Pathology, Radboud University Medical Center, Nijmegen, The Netherlands&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://warwick.ac.uk/fac/sci/dcs/people/nasir_rajpoot/"&gt;Prof. Nasir Rajpoot&lt;/a&gt;
(n.m.rajpoot@warwick.ac.uk)
University of Warwick, Coventry, UK&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Key Dates&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Deadline for &lt;a href="https://jbhi.embs.org/special-issues/computational-pathology/"&gt;submission&lt;/a&gt;: September 1, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First reviews: October 15, 2019&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Revised Manuscript due: January 15, 2020&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Final decision: March 2020&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Computer aided quantification of TSR as independent prognosticator in rectal cancer</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/automated-quantification-tsr-rectal-cancer/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-03-19T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-03-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2019-03-19:/highlights/automated-quantification-tsr-rectal-cancer/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tumor-stroma ratio (TSR) serves as an independent prognostic factor in colorectal cancer. The recent introduction of digital pathology in routine tissue diagnostics holds opportunities for automated TSR analysis. Computational pathology group member &lt;a href= "https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/oscar-geessink/"&gt;Oscar Geessink&lt;/a&gt;  and colleagues investigated the potential of computer-aided quantification of intratumoral stroma in rectal cancer whole-slide images …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Tumor-stroma ratio (TSR) serves as an independent prognostic factor in colorectal cancer. The recent introduction of digital pathology in routine tissue diagnostics holds opportunities for automated TSR analysis. Computational pathology group member &lt;a href= "https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/oscar-geessink/"&gt;Oscar Geessink&lt;/a&gt;  and colleagues investigated the potential of computer-aided quantification of intratumoral stroma in rectal cancer whole-slide images. Hot-spots inside histopathological slides of 129 rectal adenocarcinoma patients were visually assessed for TSR by two experts. A semi-automatic method based on deep learning was trained to segment all relevant tissue types in rectal cancer histology and subsequently applied to the hot-spots provided by the experts. Patients were assigned to a ‘stroma-high’ or ‘stroma-low’ group by both TSR methods (visual and automated). With stroma-low as baseline, automated TSR was found to be prognostic independent of age, gender, pT-stage, lymph node status, tumor grade, and whether adjuvant therapy was given, both for disease-specific survival (hazard ratio = 2.48 (95% confidence interval 1.29–4.78)) and for disease-free survival (hazard ratio = 2.05 (95% confidence interval 1.11–3.78)). Visually assessed TSR did not serve as an independent prognostic factor in multivariate analysis. This work has been accepted for publication by &lt;a href= "https://link.springer.com/journal/13402"&gt;Celullar Oncology&lt;/a&gt;, and appeared &lt;a href= "https://link.springer.com/article/10.1007%2Fs13402-019-00429-z"&gt;online&lt;/a&gt; this month. &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Kick-off H2020 project ExaMode</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/examode-kick-off/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2019-01-29T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2019-01-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2019-01-29:/highlights/examode-kick-off/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;20 European researchers gathered last week at the Techno-pôle in Sierre, Switserland to kick-off the European H2020 project ExaMode. Coordinated by the Institute of Information Systems of the HES-SO Valais-Wallis, &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/jeroen-van-der-laak/"&gt;Jeroen van der Laak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/francesco-ciompi/"&gt;Francesco Ciompi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/mart-van-rijthoven/"&gt;Mart van Rijthoven&lt;/a&gt; are working in partnership with the University of Padova (Italy …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;20 European researchers gathered last week at the Techno-pôle in Sierre, Switserland to kick-off the European H2020 project ExaMode. Coordinated by the Institute of Information Systems of the HES-SO Valais-Wallis, &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/jeroen-van-der-laak/"&gt;Jeroen van der Laak&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/francesco-ciompi/"&gt;Francesco Ciompi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/mart-van-rijthoven/"&gt;Mart van Rijthoven&lt;/a&gt; are working in partnership with the University of Padova (Italy), the hospital of Catania (Italy), SURFsara (Netherlands), Ontotext (Bulgaria) and MicroscopeIT (Poland) on  processing of exascale volumes of healthcare data. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The objective of the 4-year project &lt;a href="https://www.examode.eu/"&gt;ExaMode&lt;/a&gt; is to develop new prototypes for processing large volumes of medical data on exascale computing facilities. These can be used for the analysis of large quantities of histopathological images (100,000x100,000 pixel), including thin-slice images taken with a microscope required for cancer biopsies and other pathologies. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Revolutionising pathological diagnosis with digital technology&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More detailed analyses, using artificial intelligence algorithms, could lead to better results, for instance for computer-aided diagnostic assistance with quantitative parameters, often more objective than current processes. Deep learning tools are based on large volumes of training data that has insufficiently been annotated. Generating training data with limited human interaction and using semantics to better understand medical reports and the changes on the images that are described could lead to more powerful algorithms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Kick-off in Sierre&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The project partners gathered for the kick-off meeting at the Techno-Pôle in Sierre, where several research institutes of the HES-SO Valais-Wallis are located. The first day was dedicated to the presentation of the partners and to team-building activities for the consortium, and the second day to the fine-tuning of the project roadmap.  &lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>EU H2020 and KWF grant for Francesco Ciompi and Jeroen van der Laak</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/h2020-kwf/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-12-28T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-12-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2018-12-28:/highlights/h2020-kwf/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month, Computational pathology group-members &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/francesco-ciompi/"&gt;Francesco Ciompi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/jeroen-van-der-laak/"&gt;Jeroen van der Laak&lt;/a&gt; have been awarded 2 grants for performing cancer research based on deep learning techniques. Supported by funding of the &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/programmes/horizon2020/en/"&gt;European Union’s ICT12 H2020 program&lt;/a&gt;, Jeroen and Francesco will work together with a consortium of European partners on …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Last month, Computational pathology group-members &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/francesco-ciompi/"&gt;Francesco Ciompi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/jeroen-van-der-laak/"&gt;Jeroen van der Laak&lt;/a&gt; have been awarded 2 grants for performing cancer research based on deep learning techniques. Supported by funding of the &lt;a href="https://ec.europa.eu/programmes/horizon2020/en/"&gt;European Union’s ICT12 H2020 program&lt;/a&gt;, Jeroen and Francesco will work together with a consortium of European partners on the &lt;a href="https://www.examode.eu/"&gt;EXAMODE project&lt;/a&gt;. The goal of this project is to build tools based on artificial intelligence to aid pathologists in routine diagnostics via automatic analysis of digital pathology whole-slide images of cancer specimens across multiple organs. The second project (PROACTING) is in collaboration with the &lt;a href="https://www.nki.nl/"&gt;NKI&lt;/a&gt; in Amsterdam and funded by the &lt;a href="https://www.kwf.nl/onderzoek/subsidie-informatie/Pages/default.aspx"&gt;Dutch Cancer Society&lt;/a&gt; as part of the 'Onderzoek &amp;amp; Implementatie' program. With PROACTING, Jeroen and Francesco aim together with &lt;a href="https://www.nki.nl/divisions/molecular-pathology/wesseling-j-group/"&gt;Jelle Wesseling&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.nki.nl/people/lips-esther"&gt;Esther Lips&lt;/a&gt; to predict the response to neo-adjuvant treatment of breast cancer patients.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Results CAMELYON17 challenge</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/camelyon17/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2018-11-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2018-11-03:/highlights/camelyon17/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/peter-bandi/"&gt;Peter Bandi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/oscar-geessink/"&gt;Oscar Geessink&lt;/a&gt;, organizers of &lt;a href="https://camelyon17.grand-challenge.org/"&gt;CAMELYON17&lt;/a&gt;, challenged participants to move from individual metastases detection (&lt;a href="https://camelyon16.grand-challenge.org/"&gt;CAMELYON16&lt;/a&gt;) to classification of lymph node status on a patient level. Over 300 participants registered on the challenge website, of which 23 teams submitted a total of 37 algorithms before the deadline. The algorithmic …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/peter-bandi/"&gt;Peter Bandi&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/members/oscar-geessink/"&gt;Oscar Geessink&lt;/a&gt;, organizers of &lt;a href="https://camelyon17.grand-challenge.org/"&gt;CAMELYON17&lt;/a&gt;, challenged participants to move from individual metastases detection (&lt;a href="https://camelyon16.grand-challenge.org/"&gt;CAMELYON16&lt;/a&gt;) to classification of lymph node status on a patient level. Over 300 participants registered on the challenge website, of which 23 teams submitted a total of 37 algorithms before the deadline. The algorithmic details of the top-twelve best submissions are discussed in the paper that was accepted for publication in IEEE's TMI last August. Read &lt;a href="http://diagnijmegen.nl/index.php/Publication?bibkey=Band18"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; which architecture and methodology led to the best results and what pushed the highest kappa value from 0.89 to 0.93.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Radboud Science Award 2018 for Jeroen van der Laak and Geert Litjens</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/radboud_science_award_2018/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-10-06T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-10-06T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2018-10-06:/highlights/radboud_science_award_2018/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, the Radboud Science Award was awarded to Hanneke van Ouden, Thijs Eijsvogels, Jeroen van der Laak and Geert Litjens. In addition to recognizing excellent research, this award aims at connecting academic research to primary school teaching programs. Prior to and during the award ceremony, the winners were asked …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;This week, the Radboud Science Award was awarded to Hanneke van Ouden, Thijs Eijsvogels, Jeroen van der Laak and Geert Litjens. In addition to recognizing excellent research, this award aims at connecting academic research to primary school teaching programs. Prior to and during the award ceremony, the winners were asked critical questions by the students of the participating primary schools. In the coming year, the winners will work on the development of teaching material together with their colleagues, the &lt;a href="https://www.ru.nl/wetenschapsknooppunt/"&gt;Radboud Wetenschapsknooppunt&lt;/a&gt; and teachers. Videos of the interviews and the award ceremony can be found &lt;a href="https://www.ru.nl/wetenschapsknooppunt/activiteiten-voor/radboud-onderzoekers/radboud-science-awards/overzicht-winnaars/winnaars-rsa-2018/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>Automatic mitosis detection in breast cancer tissue sections</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/mitosis-detection-in-he/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-22T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2018-08-22:/highlights/mitosis-detection-in-he/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Manual counting of mitotic tumor cells in tissue sections constitutes one of the strongest prognostic markers for breast cancer. This procedure, however, is time-consuming and error-prone. &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/david-tellez/"&gt;David Tellez&lt;/a&gt; et al developed a method to automatically detect mitotic figures in H&amp;amp;E stained breast cancer tissue sections based on convolutional neural …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Manual counting of mitotic tumor cells in tissue sections constitutes one of the strongest prognostic markers for breast cancer. This procedure, however, is time-consuming and error-prone. &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/david-tellez/"&gt;David Tellez&lt;/a&gt; et al developed a method to automatically detect mitotic figures in H&amp;amp;E stained breast cancer tissue sections based on convolutional neural networks (CNNs). The system was trained in a single-center cohort and evaluated in an independent multicenter cohort from The Cancer Genome Atlas on the three tasks of the Tumor Proliferation Assessment Challenge (TUPAC). The image shows a selection of patches identified by the CNN as containing a mitotic figure. From 181 detections, 128 patches were classified as true positives by a resident pathologist, resulting in a precision score of 0.707. The work was published in &lt;a href="https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8327641/"&gt;Transactions on Medical Imaging&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>First edition MIDL 2018 great success</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/midl18-great-success/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2018-08-07T00:00:00+02:00</published><updated>2018-08-07T00:00:00+02:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2018-08-07:/highlights/midl18-great-success/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to everyone who attended &lt;a href="https://midl.amsterdam/"&gt;MIDL 2018&lt;/a&gt; and made this first edition to a great success! Among 61 posters was work from Computational Pathology group members &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/hans-pinckaers/"&gt;Hans Pinckaers&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/zaneta-swiderska-chadaj/"&gt;Zaneta Swiderska-Chadaj&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/david-tellez/"&gt;David Tellez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/mart-van-rijthoven/"&gt;Mart van Rijthoven&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/wouter-bulten/"&gt;Wouter Bulten&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A big thank you to everyone who attended &lt;a href="https://midl.amsterdam/"&gt;MIDL 2018&lt;/a&gt; and made this first edition to a great success! Among 61 posters was work from Computational Pathology group members &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/hans-pinckaers/"&gt;Hans Pinckaers&lt;/a&gt;,&lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/zaneta-swiderska-chadaj/"&gt;Zaneta Swiderska-Chadaj&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/david-tellez/"&gt;David Tellez&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/mart-van-rijthoven/"&gt;Mart van Rijthoven&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://diagnijmegen.github.io/website-pathology/members/wouter-bulten/"&gt;Wouter Bulten&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>CAMELYON16 published in JAMA</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/camelyon16-published-in-jama/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-12-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2017-12-01:/highlights/camelyon16-published-in-jama/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Diagnostic Image Analysis Group organized CAMELYON16, the first medical image analysis challenge with whole slide digital pathology images in 2016. The competition was a great success, and several of the submitted software solutions outperformed human pathologists in the detection of lymph node metastases. The results of Camelyon16 were published …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The Diagnostic Image Analysis Group organized CAMELYON16, the first medical image analysis challenge with whole slide digital pathology images in 2016. The competition was a great success, and several of the submitted software solutions outperformed human pathologists in the detection of lymph node metastases. The results of Camelyon16 were published in &lt;a href='https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jama/fullarticle/2665774'&gt;JAMA&lt;/a&gt; and covered by the national Dutch television show &lt;a href='https://nos.nl/nieuwsuur/artikel/2207329-computer-spoort-uitzaaiingen-borstkanker-beter-op-dan-patholoog.html'&gt;Nieuwsuur&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry><entry><title>NOS news article</title><link href="https://www.computationalpathologygroup.eu/highlights/nos-news-article/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2017-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</published><updated>2017-03-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>WebteamDIAG</name></author><id>tag:www.computationalpathologygroup.eu,2017-03-04:/highlights/nos-news-article/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jeroen van der Laak has contributed to a &lt;a href="https://nos.nl/artikel/2161091-computer-kan-kanker-beter-herkennen-dan-patholoog.html"&gt; news article&lt;/a&gt; from NOS about the success of Google's deep learning-based algorithm for the automatic detection of breast cancer metastasis in sentinel lymphnodes. The algorithm was trained using data from the grand challenge CAMELYON16, organized by members of the CP group. The …&lt;/p&gt;</summary><content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Jeroen van der Laak has contributed to a &lt;a href="https://nos.nl/artikel/2161091-computer-kan-kanker-beter-herkennen-dan-patholoog.html"&gt; news article&lt;/a&gt; from NOS about the success of Google's deep learning-based algorithm for the automatic detection of breast cancer metastasis in sentinel lymphnodes. The algorithm was trained using data from the grand challenge CAMELYON16, organized by members of the CP group. The algorithm outperfoms pathologists as decribed in the resulting &lt;a href="https://arxiv.org/abs/1703.02442"&gt; paper&lt;/a&gt;. More info can be found on the &lt;a href="https://ai.googleblog.com/2017/03/assisting-pathologists-in-detecting.html"&gt;Google AI Blog&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content></entry></feed>